academyxi.com 2018-11-11

# Academy Xi - Privacy Policy Academy Xi

### What is the purpose of this policy?

Academy Xi Pty Ltd (Academy Xi) is committed to the protection of your privacy and the open and transparent management of your personal information that we receive. We will always use our best endeavours to comply with the letter and spirit of our legal obligations in order to ensure Academy Xi is a safe and secure environment for its students and staff.

We may change this policy from time to time by reviewing it, revising it, or amending it. If we change this policy, we will provide you with notice of the change and access to the changed policy.

If you have any questions about this policy, please  contact our Privacy Officer.

### Why do we collect personal and sensitive information?

Our principal activity is providing classes, events, courses, email content and fostering communities within the digital and progressive space. We will only collect personal or sensitive information if it is directly related to the provision of these services, or if it is reasonably necessary for us to have the information.

### What kind of personal and sensitive information do we collect?

We will ensure that we only collect accurate personal information that we need in order to provide fostering of a digital and progressive community. We will not collect personal or sensitive information that is intrusive or excessive.

More specifically, the sorts of information that we may collect include:

(a) Student records, including records of the name, date of birth, home address and other such information relating to students. This information may be gathered as part of various application processes.

This information may be collected for a number of purposes. These include establishing the student’s identity (e.g. as an anti-fraud measure when issuing a replacement testamur), enabling communications with the student about their course and the Academy Xi services available to them, and establishing a student’s eligibility for an Academy Xi scholarship.

(b) Personnel and payroll records, including payroll and pay related records, including banking details, tax file number declaration forms, medical assessment records, attendance and leave records, recruitment, appeals, promotion and transfer records, personal employee files and service records, counselling and discipline records, performance management and evaluation records, training records, notices of separation and exit questionnaires, work health and safety and workers compensation records, records of gender, ethnicity and disability of employees for equal employment opportunity reporting purposes, recruitment applications, references and reports, records relating to character checks and criminal convictions, and fitness to work statements.

(c) Health information relating to students, including information about a student’s disabilities and needs (where applicable), to assist with the provision of appropriate services to the student, and records of counselling appointments made and attended by students as part of their interaction with the Health chapter of Student Services.

(d) We may use software to track users usage of our website anonymously, this allows us to improve the navigation of the website.

(e) By attending any of our events or classes you permit us to use any photos or footage that you may be caught in. We may use this for content or marketing purposes only. If you do not wish for us to use any content, you must let us know in writing before or after in which we will address your concerns.

### How do we collect personal and sensitive information?

We will generally collect personal and sensitive information directly from you via the internet and over the phone. We may also collect personal and sensitive information from third party sources if you have authorised us to do so.

When collecting your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to tell you our contact details, who will hold and/or have access to their personal information, what it will be used for, what other organisations (if any) routinely receive this type of personal information from us, whether the collection is required by law, whether we are likely to disclose the information to overseas recipients and, if so, the countries in which these recipients are likely to be located, what the consequences will be for you if you do not provide the information to us, and how you can access your personal information held by us.

If we obtained the information from someone else, or if you may not be aware that we have collected the information, we will further notify you that we collect, or have collected, the information, and the circumstances of collection.

### How will we hold personal and sensitive information?

We will hold your personal and sensitive information in data storage and cloud computing facilities operated by us or by reputable third party providers on our behalf.

We will take all reasonable steps to protect the information from unauthorised access, disclosure, misuse or interference. If we engage third party data storage providers, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that these providers have appropriate security procedures in place in order to protect the information from unauthorised access, disclosure, misuse or interference.

We will ensure personal information is stored securely, is not kept longer than necessary, and is disposed of appropriately.

### Can you use a pseudonym or anonymous identifier?

We will allow you to receive services via the use of a pseudonym or anonymously where it is lawful and practicable for us to allow you to do so.

We will suppress your address upon your request. If you wish to suppress your address, please contact the Privacy Officer.

### How can you access your personal information?

You can access your personal and sensitive information by contacting our Privacy Officer. We will provide a response to you within a reasonable period of time. We will provide the information to you without unreasonable expense.

We will only refuse you access to your personal and sensitive information where such refusal is permitted by law. If we do refuse access, we will provide reasons for doing so.

### How can you update your personal or sensitive information?

We will only use your personal and sensitive information for the primary purpose for which it was collected, for a directly related secondary purpose that you would reasonably have expected, and for any other purpose to which you have consented.

Before using your personal or sensitive information, we will take appropriate steps to ensure that the information is relevant, accurate, up-to-date, complete, and not misleading.

### How will we use your personal or sensitive information?

We will only use your personal and sensitive information for the primary purpose for which it was collected, for a directly related secondary purpose that you would reasonably have expected, and for any other purpose to which you have consented.

Before using your personal or sensitive information, we will take appropriate steps to ensure that the information is relevant, accurate, up-to-date, complete, and not misleading.

### When will we disclose your personal information to a third party?

We will only disclose your information to a third party if, at the time we collected your information, you were given a privacy notice to inform you that your personal information would or might be disclosed to the proposed third party recipient, if the disclosure is directly related to the purpose for which the information was collected, and we have no reason to believe that the you concerned would object to the disclosure, or if you have given your prior consent to the proposed disclosure. If we have clearly demonstrated that we’re partnered with another company in an event we may share your email and name with them. We may also share your contact details with workshop instructors who have promised to share slides with you.

Before disclosing your personal or sensitive information, we will take appropriate steps to ensure that the information is relevant, accurate, up-to-date, complete, and not misleading.

### How can you complain about a misuse of personal or sensitive information?

If you have a complaint about the way we have managed or used your personal or sensitive information, please contact our Privacy Officer at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Our Privacy Officer will endeavour to address and resolve the issues raised in your complaint, and will respond to you in writing regarding the outcome of any investigation that he or she may undertake as a result of the complaint.

If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction, or if you wish to obtain further information as to our privacy obligations, please contact:

Office of the Australian Information Commissioner

GPO Box 5218

Sydney, NSW, 2001

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### Contact Details

Academy Xi Pty Ltd  
ABN 84 608 846 822

48 Druitt St, NSW, 2000

Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Office of the Australian Information Commissioner  
GPO Box 5218  
Sydney NSW 2001

Email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4f2a213e3a263d262a3c0f202e262c61282039612e3a)
